Thanks for the buck from Fuso. How's the
CIA involved in Venez in the Venezuela
invasion?
>> What would they have you do?
>> What they would what would they have had
you do if they had sent you?
>> There are lots of moving parts when
trying to overthrow a government.
>> Uh first of all, the CIA is 100% yes
involved in whatever it is that our
government is doing right now in
Venezuela. So what you what you need to
do is operationally put pressure on
Maduro to to just run away. You want
Maduro to run away. But we know that
Trump's idea was to make him think that
he could run away.
>> Yes. And I say that because we now know
that the CIA tried to recruit his
private pilot
>> so that were he to run off like to
Havana,
>> the guy would actually land the plane in
Key West and we grab him and put him on
trial for drug trafficking. Allah Manuel
Norier,
>> which by the way would mean that no
other um target of American regime
change would ever have caused to believe
anything that we promised in the future.
>> That's exactly right. Number two, so you
well so you have to secure the the
presidential palace whether Maduro is in
it or not. Um number number two, you
have to um either co-opt the military or
bombard the military if they can't be
co-opted.
Uh number three, you have to take
control of the television and radio
stations, at least the ones in Caracus.
>> And these are CIA operations or would
these be military operations? It would
be it would be joint operations.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Since 9/11, most of of
[clears throat] these kinds of
operations would be joint with special
forces.
>> And then third, you have to take over
the the main intersections of the
capital.
But like I've said in the past, like
like we talked about on Friday,
overthrowing the government is the easy
part.
>> Yeah.
>> Right.
>> It's governing.
>> It's governing that's the hard part.
What do you do the next day?
>> Right. That's exactly that's exactly the
issue, right? And I mean, I guess you
would also need to um now there would be
a there would be cyber attacks against
Venezuelan internet infrastructure,
right? They'd probably cra want to tank
the internet, [snorts]
>> right?
>> And shut down the w the banking wire
system so that like regime officials
can't send their money overseas.
>> Exactly right. Let's talk about this
Trump declaration um of street and
fentanyl as a WMD. Um so yesterday also
at the same time it's worth noting that
the US military blew up three more
alleged drug boats this time in the
Pacific Ocean. Yeah.
>> Um according to the Pentagon they killed
uh at least eight unknown civilians,
unidentified people, supposedly narot
traffickers. They're not calling them
narot terrorists in this particular
press release. Um, so I [snorts] mean,
John, the thing that I keep coming back
to is and it and and it I don't
understand unforced errors, right? So
this president uh ran successfully uh in
a Republican primary against the Iraq
war after the fact and he basically and
you know we all know how the Iraq war
started out predicated the excuse that
was that Saddam Hussein had weapons of
mass destruction. We know that wasn't
true
>> and it was all a lie and we now know the
war was a huge mistake. Well, here we
are in Venezuela and again, we're going
to use weapons of mass destruction as an
excuse. And again, we know it's not
true, but we're going to define at least
when Bush accused um you know
[clears throat] Saddam of still having
weapons of mass destruction. At least we
knew he was talking about either
chemical, biological, or nuclear weapons
as defined under international laws,
WMDs. Here we're redefining a drug as a
weapon of mass destruction, which by
definition can't be because a weapon of
mass destruction is an individual weapon
that goes off and kills lots and lots of
people all at once.
>> Like no drug can do that. Um so it's
like, you know, you can give drugs to
lots and lots of people. You could
poison the water supply with drugs. That
still wouldn't make it a weapon of mass
destruction. So
>> um but I guess he can do this. And I
mean, why I guess the whole thing is if
you're trying to overthrow Venezuela,
why go about it in the same way that
your adversary failed to do the same
thing? [clears throat]
>> I I I I
don't understand it. And not only do I
not understand it, I disagree with it
because
declaring fentinel a weapon of mass
destruction
so cheapens the process
that it it makes the whole process
kind of
laughable and ineffective.
You know, like declaring Antifa
a terrorist organization. Did you see
this video? I I posted it on Facebook
yesterday. It's these two It's these two
guys. They're both uh military veterans
and they they're filming themselves.
They go up to FBI headquarters and they
said, "Hi, we're both um Antifa field
commanders. We want to turn ourselves
in." [laughter]
And the FBI agent's like, "Uh, I'm not
really sure what to do. Hang here." And
they won't they won't take them. They're
like, "Well, the president declared it a
a um a terrorist group and we're both
anti-fascist and so you know I we're
both from command."
>> Yeah. And the FBI is like, "We we don't
know what to do. You should just leave."
[laughter]
>> Same thing. Fentinel, weapon of mass
destruction.
>> Come on. And it's like and and we're not
even and fentinyl that Venezuela doesn't
make fentinel.
>> No, it doesn't make
>> and whatever they're sending, which is
probably cocaine, is not going to the
United States anyway.
>> No, it's going to to Western Europe.
>> Yeah. Um let's talk a bit about this um
MI6 lady, Bla1 Metroelli. She's the
first um the MI6 is old. They I didn't
realize it was 116 years old. um
according to uh the press, she's the
first woman to run MI6 and she gave a
big policy speech and basically she went
on and on and on about how the biggest
threat to I guess the UK and to Europe
in general is Russia and specifically it
all comes down to the Russo Ukrainian
war. Um I I thought that was some pretty
I thought that was really kind of sad.
She talked a little bit about uh AI and
the uh how it can be used for you know
as it'll how it's a threat but also how
it can be useful also and you know so
she she seems like she comes from the
tech side of things but it didn't seem
like very did not seem I guess what did
you think of her analysis is my question
>> not convincing
not convincing yes AI is a very big
problem but you can't say that Russia is
the gravest threat uh to you know
freedom and democracy on the face of the
earth. Where do you come up with that?
Um misuse of technology could be China
could be. Russia is practically
bankrupt. It has a population that is
shrinking to the point where at its
current birth rate there will be no
Russians
in a 100 years.
>> Obviously that won't happen but that is
a funny factoid.
>> [laughter]
>> Um well they'll have and whoever's left
will have a lot of room.
>> A lot of space.
>> Yeah. A lot of space.
>> But no I this I I'm just not seeing
Russia as this, you know, in yourface
global immediate threat that has to No,
I I just I'm not
>> I mean do you think any nation state is
even China or is it is it I think that
the real threats are going to be more
amorphous like climate change which may
not be specific nation state versus
nation state.
>> That's right.
>> [music]
[music]